Khai Nguyen

Email: khainb@utexas.com Website: khainb.github.io Contact: (+84) 399417566

Research Interest

A central theme of my research focuses on making scalable Optimal Transport. In particular, I develop dimensional reduction methods and sub-sampling methods (mini-batch techniques) for Optimal Transport. I am also interested in applications that need to deal with probability measures.

EDUCATION

University of Texas at Austin

Austin, Texas, USA 2021–Present

Ph.D. in Statistics at Department of Statistics and Data Sciences

Hanoi, Vietnam

2015 - 2020

Hanoi University of Science and Technology (HUST)

Bachelor in Information System (another name of Computer Science)

- GPA: 3.61/4.00, Major GPA: 3.71/4.00, Top: 1%, graduated with Excellent Degree.
- Thesis: "Distributional Sliced-Wasserstein and Applications to Generative Modeling"

EXPERIENCE

VinAI Research, website: www.vinai.io

Hanoi, Vietnam

AI Research Resident

2019 - 2021

- Research topics: Deep Generative Models, Optimal Transport
- Advisors: Dr. Hung Bui (Director of VinAI Research), Dr. Nhat Ho (Assistant Professor at UT, Austin)
- Skills gained: Deep Generative Models (VAEs, GANs, Flows, and Score matching models, etc), Optimal Transport (Sinkhorn algorithm, Slicing approaches, Barycenter, variants of Wasserstein distance, Gromov Wasserstein, etc, Applications of OT (Wasserstein Autoencoder, Wasserstein GAN, Color Transfer, etc)

Data Science Laboratory (HUST), website: ds.soict.hust.edu.vn

Hanoi, Vietnam 2018–2020

Undergraduate Research Student

- Research topics: Probabilistic Graphical Model, Continual Learning.
- Skills gained: Fundamental Machine Learning and Deep Learning, Topic models, Bayesian inference, Variational techniques, etc

PUBLICATIONS

An Efficient Mini-batch Method via Partial Transportation

Khai Nguyen, Dang Nguyen, Tung Pham, Nhat Ho

- Arxiv: https://arxiv.org/abs/2108.09645
- Under review

BoMb-OT: On Batch of Mini-batches Optimal Transport

Khai Nguyen, Quoc Nguyen, Nhat Ho, Tung Pham, Hung Bui, Dinh Phung, Trung Le

- Arxiv: https://arxiv.org/abs/2102.05912
- Under review

Structured Dropout Variational Inference for Bayesian Neural Networks

Son Nguyen, Duong Nguyen, **Khai Nguyen**, Nhat Ho, Khoat Than, Hung Bui

- Arxiv: https://arxiv.org/abs/2102.07927
- Under review

Improving Relational Regularized Autoencoders with Spherical Sliced Fused Gromov Wasserstein Khai Nguyen, Son Nguyen, Nhat Ho, Tung Pham, Hung Bui

- Arxiv: https://arxiv.org/abs/2010.01787
- International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) 2021

Distributional Sliced-Wasserstein and Applications to Generative Modeling

Khai Nguyen, Nhat Ho, Tung Pham, Hung Bui

- Arxiv: https://arxiv.org/abs/2002.07367
- International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) 2021 (Spotlight 3.8%)

Professional services

- Reviewer at International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2021
- Reviewer at Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2021
- Reviewer at International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) 2022

AWARDS

• Doctoral Fellowship of University of Texas at Austin

2021

• Third Prize of Scientific Research Student Award of Hanoi University of Science and Technology

2019

OTHER ACTIVITIES

Top 2% (19 over 1317) in Plant Pathology Challenge

CVPR 2020

Fine-Grained Visual Categorization (FGVC) workshop

May 2020

Southeast Asia Machine Learning School

Greater Jakarta, Indonesia

Universitas Indonesia

July 2019

Technical Talk
Hanoi, Vietnam

Data Science Laboratory (HUST)

June 2019

- Make an introduction to Optimal Transport and its applications in deep generative models.
- Slides: http://bit.ly/3pDEp1f

Teaching Assistant

Hanoi, Vietnam

April - May, 2019

Data Science Laboratory (HUST)

- Run a small course on fundamental machine learning models such as linear regressions, logistic regressions,
 k-nearest neighbors, support vector machines, and neural networks for new members.
- Make a tutorial about training deep neural networks with Tensorflow a deep learning framework.

Top 12 in The 4th AutoML Challenge (AutoML3+)

PAKDD 2019

Provided and Sponsored by 4Paradigm, ChaLearn, Microsoft and Amazon

Jan 2019

LANGUAGES

- Vietnamese: Native
- English: IELTS 7.5 Overall, 9.0 Reading, 8.0 Listening, 6.5 Writing, 6.5 Speaking.

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

• Python: Proficient

 $Libraries:\ Pytorch,\ Scikit\text{-}Learn,\ etc$

Java: Familiar C/C++: Familiar